Inventory of the Iranian Political Opposition Literature collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Hizb-i Tudah-'i Īrān, 1967-1993; 1-12 (Box 1-12)
  - Monographs, booklets, and pamphlets (Folder 6-12)
    - Nāmeh-yi tuzihī bā rufuqā-i hizbī, monograph, 1364 Mordād (1985 August) (Folder 11: 1)
    - Naqd bar barnāmeh-yi Gutā, (Florence: Mazdak), booklet, circa 1350s (1970s) (Folder 11: 2)
      Part of the series "Marx Engels Selected Works"
    - Naqsh-i Isrā'il va rizhīm-i Pahlavī dar khāvar mīyāneh, M. Shu'ā'īyān (Florence: Mazdak), booklet, 1356 (1977) (Folder 11: 3)
    - Naqsh-i shaksīat dar tārīkh, Georgi Plekhanov (Florence: Mazdak), monograph, 1348 Tabistan (1969) (Folder 11: 4)
    - Natij-i va chashmandazehā, Leon Trotsky (Brussels: Intishārat-i Tali'eh), monograph, 1355 Tir (1976 July) (Folder 11: 5)
    - Nazarī beh junbish-i kārgarī va kumunīstī dar īrān, 'Abd al-Samad Kambakhsh (Stockholm: Hizb-i Tudah), monograph, 1353 (1974) (Folder 11: 6)
    - Pīrāmun barkhī masā'il-i ijtemā-i, iqtisādī va sīyāsī-yi īrān dar mārhālih kununī, (S.l.: Hizb-i Tudah), monograph, undated (Folder 11: 7)
    - Pirāmun-i mosāvabat-i kunfirāns-i millī Hizb-i Tudah-'i Īrān, (S.l.: Hizb-i Tudah), monograph, 1363 (1984) (Folder 11: 8)
    - Pīsh bi-su-yi vahdat-i usulī Mārksīst-Linīnīst-hā, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Hizb-i Tudah-'i Īrān Khārij az Kishvar), monograph, 1355 (1976) (Folder 11: 9)
    - Rostai īrān dar intizir tahvul, Amir-Gialzar Nikaian, (Tehran: 16 Azar), monograph, 1360 (1981) (Folder 11: 10)
    - Ruhānīat, susīālīsm, va barnāmeh-yi mā, Rosa Luxemburg (Florence: Mazdak), monograph, 1354 (1976) (Folder 11: 11)
    - Safahtī chand az junbish-i kārgarī va kumunīst-i īrān dar durān-i avval-i sāltānāt-i Rizā Shāh (1922-1933), Aavansian Aardishir, monograph, 1358 (1979) (Folder 11: 12)
    - Sālnāmeh-yi Tudah, beh munasbat-i panjahumīn sālgard-i Hizb-i Kumunīst-i Īrān va sīyyumīn sālgard-i Hizb-i Tudah-'i Īrān, (Stassfurt: Hizb-i Tudah), monograph, 1349 (1970) (Folder 11: 13)
    - Sarnivisht-i tārikhī Hizb-i Tudah-'i Īrān, Babak Amir Khosrowi (France: Rivero), monograph, 1365 Bahman (1987 February) (Folder 12: 1)
    - "Sāzmān-hā-yi Hizb-i Tudah-'i Irān 'Pulunum 19' va 'Kunferāns-i Millī' rā mahkum mī kunand," published by the Tudah Party of France, booklet, 1365 Shahrivar (1986 August) (Folder 12: 2)
    - Shīshomin nāmeh-yi sar goshādeh beh Chirīk'hā-yi Fadā'ī-i, Mustafā Shu'ā'īyān (Florence, Italy: Intishārat-i Mazdak), monograph, circa 1355 (1976) (Folder 12: 3)
    - Sīmā-yi mardum-i Hizb-i Tudah-'i Īrān, F.M. Javānshir (Iran: 16 Azar), monograph, 1360 Āzar (1981 December) (Folder 12: 4)
    - "Solidarity with the Tudeh Party of Iran," (London: The Tudeh Party of Iran in Britain), booklet, circa 1984 (Folder 12: 5)
    - Susīālism va mahzab, rush-i Hizb-i Kārgarān nisbat beh mahzab, V.I. Lenin, booklet, undated (Folder 12: 6)
    - Susīālism-i 'alāmī, āmuzish-i khalq-i inqilāb-i ijtimā'i, A. Shahbazi (Carbondale, Ill.: Sāzmān-i Havādārān-i Hizb), pamphlet, 1360 (1981) (Folder 12: 7)
    - Tajribah-i tārikhī-yi rāh-i rushd-i ghayr'i sarmāyan'darī, V. Solodovnikov (Tehran: Payk-i Irān), chāp-2, monograph, 1359 (1980) (Folder 12: 8)
    - Takāmil-tab'īat bamhīat-ars: az majāleh "Donyā", Dr. Taqi Arāni (Florence: Mazdak), booklet, circa 1350s (1970s) (Folder 12: 9)
    - Tarh'hāī-i pīshnāhādi-yi Hizb-i Tudah-'i Īrān dar bāreh-yi dīgarunsāzi va nusāzī-yi javānib-i gunāgun jāmeh'i īrān, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Hizb), monograph, 1358 (1979) (Folder 12: 10)
    - Tufān tardikī mi shud va maqālat-i dīgar, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Hizb), booklet, 1359 (1980) (Folder 12: 11)
    - T'urī "tablī masālihāneh" anherāf az Mārksīsm Linīnīsm, Turaj Heydari (S.l.: Intishārat-i Hizb), monograph, 1357 (1978) (Folder 12: 12)
    - T'urī-hā-yi gamrāhi yā gamrāhi-hā-yi t'urīkī?, Hizb-i Tudah-'i Īrān, monograph, 1365 (1986) (Folder 12: 13)
    - Uktubir va zid uktubir, Heidar Mihrgan, (Intishārat-i Hizb), monograph, 1365 (1986) (Folder 12: 14)
    - Vazāyaf-i Sāzmān-hā-yi javānān, V.I. Lenin (Florence: Mazdak), booklets, circa 1350s (1970s) (Folder 12: 15)
    - V.I. Linīn dar bāreh-yi Mārksīsm, (Florence: Mazdak), booklet, undated (Folder 12: 16)
    - Yād dāsht-hā-yi zindān, Ihsan Tabari, monograph, undated (Folder 12: 17)
    - Yād dāsht-hā-yi zindān (1928-1942), Aardishir Aavanisian (S.l.: Hizb-i Tudah), monograph, 1358 (1979) (Folder 12: 18)
    - Yik tahlīl-i 'amumī, jāmeh-yi īrān dar durān-i Rizā Shāh, Ihsan Tabari (Stockholm: Hizb-i Tudah), monograph, 1356 (1977) (Folder 12: 19)
  - Assorted administrative booklets, 1352 (1973), undated. (Folder 12: 20)
    Includes amended constitution
- Hizb-i Kumunīst-i Īrān, 1982-1989; 13 (Box 13)
  Arranged in two groups: Serials and Booklets
  - Serials (Folder 13)
    - Bi-su-yi susīālism, neshrī-yi t'urīk-i Hizb-i Kumunīst-i Īrān, shumārah-i 2, journal, 1364 Āzar (1985 November) (Folder 13: 1-2)
    - Bolshevik Message, nos. 1, 3, 7, newsletters, 1983 June-1985 January (Folder 13: 3)
    - Kumunīst, urgān-i markazī-yi Hizb-i Kumunīst-i Īrān, (London: Hizb-i Kumunīst-i Īran), newspapers and journal, 1362-1367 (1983-1989) (Folder 13: 4-8)
      - Sāl-i 1-4, shumārah-i 1-3, 7, 21-26, 31, 1362 Ābān-1366 Farvardīn (1983 November-1987 April) (Folder 13: 4-7)
      - Sāl-i 6, shumārah-i 45-47, 1367 Ābān-Day (1988 November-1989 January) (Folder 13: 8)
    - Report, biweekly newsletter, nos. 4, 6-7, 1985 December-1986 January (Folder 13: 9)
    - Risāneh, shumārah-i 2, newsletter, 1364 Shahrivar (1985 August) (Folder 13: 10)
    - Uktubir, neshrī-yi kumiteh-yi khārij az kishvar-i Hizb-i Kumunīst-i Īrān, sāl-i 1, shumārah-i 1, newspaper, 1363 Mordād (1984 August) (Folder 13: 11)
  - Booklets (Folder 13)
    - Bar nāmeh-yi Hizb-i Kumunīst-i Īrān; esās nāmeh-yi Hizb-i Kumunīst-i Īrān, 1362 Shahrivar (1983 September) (Folder 13: 12)
    - Bīyānieh, payām-hā va qat nāmeh-hā-yi kungreh-i muāsis-i Hizb-i Kumunīst-i Īrān, 1362 Shahrivar (1983 September) (Folder 13: 13)
    - Usul va sabuk'kār: hawzah-hā-yi hizbī, (West Germany: Intishārat-i Hizb-i Kumunīst-i Īrān), 1363 Farvardīn (1984 April) (Folder 13: 14)
- Ittihādiyah-i Kumunīst'hā-'i Īrān, 1976-1986; 13-14 (Box 13-14)
  Arranged in two groups: Serials and Monographs and booklets
  - Serials (Folder 13-14)
    - Haqiqat, urgān-i Ittihādiyāh-'i Kumunīst-hā-'i Īrān, (Aarhu, Denmark: Intishārat-i Ittihādiyah-'i Kumunīst-hā-'i Īrān), newsletters, 1355-1358 (1976-1979), undated (Folder 13-14)
      - Shumārah-i 1-5, 1355 Mehr-Bahman (1976 October 1976-1977 February) (Folder 13: 15)
      - Shumārah-i 9, 13-14, 16-24, 1356 Khordād-1357 Āzar (1977 June-1978 December) (Folder 13: 16-17)
      - Shumārah-i 15 and unknown, 1358 Ābān (1979 October), undated (Folder 14: 1)
    - Rahā'i, shumārah-i 1-3, (Solna, Sweden: Guruh-i Ittihādiyāh-'i Kumunīst), journals, 1357 Ordibihisht-Āzar (1978 April-October) (Folder 14: 2)
    - Sarbidārān va sāltānāt-i siyāh Khomeinī, shumārah-i 6, pamphlet, 1361 Farvardīn (1982 April) (Folder 14: 3)
  - Monographs and booklets (Folder 14)
    - Afshāi asnād-i Sāvāk 2: ittilā'atī dar bāreh-yi pīsh az 100 nafar az muzduran-i Sāvāk, booklet, 1358 Esfand (1980 March) (Folder 14: 4)
    - Bahs dar masā'lah-i arzī: pāsukhī beh naqd-i 'mobārzin-i rāh-i ārmān kārgār', booklet, 1358 Āzar (1979 December) (Folder 14: 5)
    - Dar bāreh-yi impirīālistī-yi Amrīkā va Shurāvī qadartarīn dushmanān bashrīat sitamdidāh 'dar bāreh-yi jabhah-yi keh gardanandīgān-i sāzmān-i chirīk'hā-yi fadā'ī-i mīkhāhand tashkīl dahand', booklet, 1359 Khordād (1980 June) (Folder 14: 6)
    - Dar bāreh-yi internāsiunālīsm prulitārī, booklet, 1365 Day (1986 December) (Folder 14: 7)
    - "Dimukrāsī naqas" barasī-yi sālhā 1320-32, M.A. Javid (Angered, Sweden: I.P.S.C.), daftar-i 1, monograph, 1357 Khordād (1976 June) (Folder 14: 8)
    - Gozārashī az sivvumīn shurāi ittihād-i kumunīst'hā-'i īrān, Havādāran ittihādiyāh-'i kumunīst'hā-'i īrān dar Inglistān, booklet, undated (Folder 14: 9)
    - Junbish-i dānishjuī-yi īrān (yik barrasī-yi mokhtāsar), monograph, 1355 Mehr (1976 October) (Folder 14: 10)
    - Rifurm-i arzī impirīālistī va mobārizāh tabaqāti dar īrān, (serī taqīqat dar bāreh-yi sakht hamāh-i īrān), monograph and photocopy, 1359 (1980) (Folder 14: 11-12)
    - Sīlsālāh maqālat-i āmuzāsh-i Mārksisti barāi kārgarān: tārīkhcheh junbish-i kārgarī, daftar-i 1, booklet, 1356 Khordād (1977 May) (Folder 14: 13)
- Kurdish Political Opposition Groups, 1973-1989; 14-17 (Box 14-17: 13)
  Includes the bulk of the collection's Kurdish language materials.
  Arranged by organization, then in groups by physical format
  - Hizb-i Dimukratīk-i Kurdistān, 1356-1366 (1977-1988) (Folder 14-15)
    - Serials (Folder 14-15)
      - Akhbār-i kurdistān az rādīo sedāi-yi kurdistān, shumārah-i 14, 20, 26, 33-34, bulletins, 1361 Khordād-1362 Tīr (1982 January-1983 July) (Folder 14: 14)
      - Bulitan-i khabarī-yi kurdistān, shumārah-i 215-220, 224, 232-234, bulletins, 1366-1368 (1988-1989) (Folder 14: 15)
      - Bulitan-i khabarī-yi kurdistān īrān, shumārah-i 36, 38-42, 68, 100, 112-113, bulletins, 1362 Mordād-1364 Khordād (1983 August-1985 May) (Folder 14: 16)
      - Kurdistān, (Paris: P.D.K.I.), shumārah-i 75, 83, 85, 96-97, journals, 1360 Ordibihisht-1363 Tīr (1981 May-1984 July) (Folder 14: 17)
      - Kurdistān, (Paris: P.D.K.I.), shumārah-i 98-106, 134, journals, 1363 Mordād-1366 Bahman (1984 August-1988 January) (Folder 15: 1-3)
    - Booklets (Folder 15)
      - Bahs-i kutāhī dar bāreh-yi susīālism, (Paris: P.D.K.I.), booklets, 1362 Mordād (1983 August) (Folder 15: 4)
      - Chand shanad-i pīrāmun ravābit-i Hizb-i Dimukrat-i Kurdistān Īrān bā shurā-yi millī muqāvāmāt, (Paris: P.D.K.I.), booklets, 1364 Ordibihisht (1985 May) (Folder 15: 5)
      - Kurdistan Īrān, Dr. Abdul Rahman Ghasmelu, (Paris: Sedag), chāp-i 1, booklet, 1977 June (Folder 15: 6)
    - Administrative pamphlets, in Persian and Kurdish, 1352-1367 (1973-1988) (Folder 15: 7-8)
      Includes constitution and minutes from the second and third congress meetings
  - Kumahlah, 1358-1364 (1979-1985) (Folder 15-17)
    Includes printed matter from Sāzmān-i Inqilābī-i Zahmatkashān-i Kurdistān Īrān and Sāzmān-i Kurdistān Hizb-i Kumunīst-i Īrān
    - Serials (Folder 15-16)
      - Khabar nāmeh-yi Kumahlah, shumārah-i 16, 49, 68, 173, 177, newsletters and journals, 1359-1362 (1980-1983) (Folder 15: 9-10)
      - Khabar nāmeh-yi Kurdistān, shumārah-i 4, newsletter, 1358 (1979) (Folder 15: 11)
      - "Komala Document Series," nos. 2 and 5, (Uppsala, Sweden: Esmail Shrifzade), pamphlets, 1980 April-June (Folder 15: 12)
        Includes English translation of speech made by a member of Komala to the people of Mahabad, June 1980, and a pamphlet titled "Resistance to the Huge Military Attack on Kurdistan, and to the Repression of Workers and Students"
      - "Komala Translation Series," nos. 1 and 3, (London: Komala), pamphlets, 1981 March and August (Folder 15: 13)
        Includes English translations of resolutions adopted at 2 Komala congress meetings
      - Kurdistan, nos. 1-2, journals, 1983 January and March/April (Folder 15: 4)
        In Kurdish
      - Pīshraw (Persian), 1361-1364 (1982-1985) (Folder 16: 1-4)
        Includes two different versions of this journal, probably published in different locations
      - Pīshraw (Kurdish), journals, 1362-1363 (1983-1984) (Folder 16: 5-6)
      - Rādīo sedāi inqilāb-i Īrān, shumārah-i 2, 8-9, 18-19, 21, pamphlets, 1361-1362 (1982-1983) (Folder 16: 7)
      - Rigai-yi gehl, journals, 1359-1364 (1980-1985) (Folder 16-17)
        In Persian and Kurdish
        - Shumārah-i 7, 1359 Ordibihist (1980 April) (Folder 16: 8)
        - Sāl-i 1, shumārah-i 1, 3, 4-8, 10-11, 1361 Āzar-1362 Ābān (1982 November-1983 October) (Folder 16: 9-11)
        - Sāl-i 2-3, shumārah-i 12, 14-16, 19, 30, 33-35, 1362 Āzar-1364 Ābān (1983 November-1984 October) (Folder 17: 1-2)
      - Sangar-i dānishjoo, sāl-i 1, shumārah-i 1, pamphlet, 1361 (1982) (Folder 17: 3)
      - Shurash, urgān-i sāzmān-i zahmatkashān-i Kurdistān Īrān, bound journal, 1358 Bahman (1979 January) (Folder 17: 4)
      - The Voice of Kurdistan, no. 1, (Association of Kurdistan Students Abroad in Britain), journal, undated (Folder 17: 5)
    - Monographs and booklets (Folder 17)
      - Barassī-i jang-i irtijā'i Hizb-i Dimukrat 'alih kumahlah: sālsāleh-yi guftarī az sedā'i inqilābī-i īrān, monograph, 1364 Shahrivar (1985 August) (Folder 17: 6)
      - Cheh kisāni 'avamfarībī mī kunand?!, Sāzmān-i Chirīk'hā-yi Fadā'ī-i Khalq-i Īrān shākh-i Kurdistān, booklet, undated (Folder 17: 7)
      - Faj'ah-i urāmān, shumārah-i 1-2, booklets, 1363 (1984) (Folder 17: 8)
      - Hizb-i dimukrat bar 'alāyhi kumalah bā har murtajī'i hamsidā mī-shavad, (West Germany?: Kumahlah), booklet, 1361 (1982) (Folder 17: 9)
      - Junbish-i muqāvamat-i khalq-i Kurd va masā'lih vābastegī, booklet, 1359 (1980) (Folder 17: 10)
      - Khatāb beh rafīqā-yi Fadā'ī-i dar murad, booklet, 1358 (1979) (Folder 17: 11)
      - Kumahlah va masā'lih-yi millī dar Kurdistān, (West Germany: Kumalah), booklet, undated (Folder 17: 12)
      - Nāmeh'hā-i az dur (nāmeh-yi sivvum) dar bāreh-yi milīshīā prulitārīā'i, V.I. Lenin (S.l.: Intishārat-i Kumahlah), booklet, undated (Folder 17: 13)
      - Naqdī bar dīdgāh'hā-yi "kumahlah," (S.l.: Intishārat-i Chirīk'hā-yi Fadā'ī-i Khalq-i Irān), monograph, circa 1360s (1980s) (Folder 17: 14)
      - Pulunum-i kumiteh-yi markazī-i kumahlah, pamphlet, 1364 Tīr (1985 June) (Folder 17: 15)
      - Tāwtī'āh-yi jang'āfruzanāh-yi hay'at-i hakimāh-i irtijā'i-yi īrān va 'arāq rā kih dar jihat-i sarkub-i zahmatkashān va khalqhā-yi har daw kishvar ast, khunsā kunīm, (Tehran: Kumahlah), booklet, 1359 (1980) (Folder 17: 16)
    - Administrative pamphlets, in Persian and Kurdish, 1360-1361 (1981-1982) (Folder 17: 17-18)
- Sāzmān-i Chirīk'hā-yi Fadā'ī-i Khalq-i Īrān, 1970-1991; 18-35 (Box 18-35: 17-18)
  Includes printed matter published by the People's Sacrifice Guerrillas of Iran and its supporters.
  Arranged in three groups: Serials, Monographs and booklets, and General printed matter
  - Serials (Folder 18-26)
    - 19 Bahman t'urik, shumarah-i 2-4; 1-3, (S.l.: s.n.), serial monographs, 1354 Day-1366 Āzar (1974 December-1977 November) (Folder 18: 1-5)
    - Aksariyat, (West Germany: Sāzmān-i Fadā'yān-i Khalq-i Irān dar Khārij az Kishvar), newspapers, 1363-1369 (1984-1991) (Folder 18-19)
      - Sāl-i 1, shumārah-i 1-20, 29, 1363 (1984) (Folder 18: 6-7)
      - Sāl-i 2, shumārah-i 50, 1364 Farvardin (1985 April) (Folder 18: 8)
      - Sāl-i 5, shumārah-i 239, 242-248, 250, 1367 Day-Esfand (1988 December-1989 March) (Folder 18: 9-10)
      - Sāl-i 6, shumārah-i 251-253, 255-258, 1368 Farvardin-Khordād (1989 April-May) (Folder 18: 11)
      - Sāl-i 6, shumārah-i 260-264, 266-278, 281-298, 1368 Mordād-Esfand (1989 July-1990 March) (Folder 19: 1-3)
      - Sāl-i 7, shumārah-i 299-300, 1369 Farvardin (1990 April) (Folder 19: 4)
      - Sāl-i 8, shumārah-i 303, 307, 309-311, 320-325, 328-339, 341, 1369 Ordibihisht-Esfand (1990 May-1991 March) (Folder 19: 5-7)
    - Āmuzāsh-hā-i az inqilāb va susiālism, shumārah-i 4 va 10, (S.l: Intishārat-i Sāzmān-i Chirik'hā-yi Fadā'i-i Khalq), 1360 Āzar va 1364 Shahrivar (1981 November and 1985 August) (Folder 19: 8-9)
    - 'Asr-i 'amal, shumārah-i 1-2, 5-6, (Karlsruhe, West Germany: s.n.), journals, circa 1354 (1975) (Folder 19: 10-11)
    - Bami āstar, neshrī-yi havādārān-i Sāzmān-i Chirīk'hā-yi Fadā'ī-i Khalq-i Īrān-i sistan va Baluchistān, shumārah-i 25-26, 28-29, 33-35, 42, 47, 49, 51, 1363 Ābān-1365 Āzar (1984 October-1986 November) (Folder 20: 1-3)
    - Bulitan-i mabāhsat, Sāzmān-i Dānishjuyān-i Īrāni dar Amrikā havādārān-i Sāzmān-i Chirīk'hā-yi Fadā'ī-i Khalq, (S.l.: s.n.), journals, 1350s-1361 (1970s-1982) (Folder 20: 4-7)
      - "Linīnism va Tirutskism," shumārah-i 2, Sāzmān-i dānishjuyān-i īrānī dar āllemān federāl va berlin qarbī havādār sāzmān-i chirīk'hā-yi fadā'ī-i khalq-i īrān, journals, 1361 Khordād (1982 May) (Folder 20: 4)
      - "Tarāznāmeh va chishm'andāz," shumārah-i 1, Sāzmān-i Dānishjuyān-i Īrān dar Amrikā, pamphlet, probably 1361 (1982) (Folder 20: 5)
      - "Dar bāreh-yi durān," shumārah-i 6, journals, 1361 Ābān (1982 October) (Folder 20: 6)
      - "Inqilāb-i īrān va vazāyif-i prulitārīā," shumārah-i 7, (West Germany?: Intishārat-i Sāzmān), journals, 1361 Bahman (1982 December) (Folder 20: 7)
    - Bulitan-i sīyāsī, sāzmān-i fadā'yan-i khalq-i īrān (aksariyat), shumārah-i 17-18, 20-25, 27, 29-30, 33, 36, 38-42, journals, 1361 Āzar-1362 Shahrivar (1982 November-1983 August) (Folder 20: 8-9)
    - Fadā'ī-i, urgān-i markazī-yi Sāzmān-i Chirīk'hā-yi Fadā'ī-i Khalq-i Īrān, dawrah-yi 2, sāl-i 1-3, shumārah-i 1-2, 5, 26-27, 32, newspapers, 1363 Tīr-1365 Bahman (1984 June-1986 January) (Folder 20: 10)
    - I'lamiyah-hā va bayāniyāh'hā-yi Sāzmān-i Chirīk'hā-yi Fadā-ī'i Khalq dar sāl-i 1357, bound newsletters, (S.l: s.n.), 1357 (1978) (Folder 20: 11)
    - I'lamiyah-hā va bayāniyāh'hā-yi Sāzmān-i Chirīk'hā-yi Fadā-ī'i Khalq dar sāl-i 1357(contd.), monograph, (S.l: s.n.), 1357 (1978) (Folder 21: 1)
      Same content as the bound newsletters in Box 20, folder 11, but published in book form
    - Iran in Resistance, (S.l.: ISAUS), journals, 1983-1987 (Folder 21)
      - Volume 1, nos. 1-2, 1983 September-November (Folder 21: 2)
      - Volume 1, nos. 1-3, 1984 January/February-May/June (Folder 21: 3)
      - Nos. 6-7, 9-10, 15-17, 1984 July/August-1987 July/August (Folder 21: 4-5)
    - Iran Rundschau, number 3, journal of the Iranian Student Association in Frankfurt, circa 1981 (Folder 21: 6)
    - Iran Solidarity, (S.l.: ISA), newspaper, 1984 May (Folder 21: 7)
    - Jahān, neshrī-yi dānishjuyān-i havādārān-i Sāzmān-i Chirīk'hā-yi Fadā'ī-i Khalq-i Īrān dar Urupā va Amrikā, (S.l.: s.n.), newspapers and magazines, 1360-1365 (1982-1986) (Folder 21-22)
      - Sāl-i 1, shumārah-i 1-7, 1360 Day-1361 Āzar (1982 January-December) (Folder 21: 8-9)
      - Sāl-i 2, shumārah-i 8-16, 1361 Bahman-1362 Āzar (1983 February-November/December) (Folder 21: 10-13)
        Also includes a special unnumbered issue titled "Vizheh-yi aksiyun sarāsari 7 Nuvambir," 1361 Ābān (1983 November)
      - Sāl-i 3, shumārah-i 17-18, 1362 Day/Bahman-Esfand/Farvardin (1983 January/February-March/April) (Folder 21: 14)
      - Sāl-i 3, shumārah-i 19-22, 1363 Ordibihisht-Tir (1984 May-July) (Folder 22: 1-2)
      - Sāl-i 5, shumārah-i 47, 1365 Mehr (1986 October) (Folder 22: 3)
    - Jangal, sāl-i 1, shumārah-i 1-3, (Solna, Sweden: s.n.), booklet and magazines, 1362 Day-1363 Farvardin (1983 December-1984 March) (Folder 22: 4)
    - Kār (or "Travail"), no. 4, journals, 1980 October (Folder 22: 5)
      Includes articles from the Persian language publication, translated into French
    - Kār (or "Labour"), nos. 85 and 108, journals, 1981 January and May (Folder 22: 6)
    - "Khabar nāmeh," neshrī-yi chirīk'hā-yi fadā'ī-i khalq-i īrān-mazandarān," newsletters, 1358-1360 (1979-1981) (Folder 22)
      - Shumārah-i 13-18, 1358 Bahman-1359 Farvardin (1979 January-March) (Folder 22: 7-8)
      - Shumārah-i 22-26, 28-30, 33, 38-42, 49, 1359 Ordibihisht-Bahman (1980 April-1981 January) (Folder 22: 9-12)
      - Shumārah-i 61 va zamimeh-yi shumārah-i 57, 1360 Khordād and Ordibihisht (1981 April and May) (Folder 22: 13)
    - Nabard, sāl-i 1-2, shumārah-'i 1-5, journals, 1362 Ābān-1363 Ābān (1983 October-1984 October) (Folder 22: 14-15)
    - Nabard-i dānishjoo, sāl-i 1, shumārah-i 7, urgān-i Sāzmān-i Dānishjuyān-i Pīshgām, journal, 1359 Ordibihisht 16 (1970 April) (Folder 22: 16)
      Photocopy
    - Nabard-i dānishāmuz, sāl-i 1, shumārah-i 4, 7, 10, urgān-i sarāsarī-yi dānishāmuzān-i pīshgām, newsletters, 1358 Day 26-Esfand 7 (1979 December-February). (Folder 23: 1)
    - Nabard-i Khalq, urgān-i sāzmān-i chirīk'hā-yi fadā'ī-i khalq-ī irān, journals, 1353-1359 (1972-1980), undated (Folder 23-24)
      - Zamīmeh, unnumbered, 1353 Esfand (1972 February) (Folder 23: 2)
      - Shumārah-i 2-6, 1353 Farvardīn-1354 Ordibihisht (1974 March-1975 April) (Folder 23: 3-4)
      - Shumārah-i 1 va 7, 1355 Khordād (1976 May) (Folder 23: 5)
      - Shumārah-i 4 va 7, 1357 Bahman va 1358 Mordād (1978 January and 1989 July) (Folder 23: 6)
      - Shumārah-i 7, 1358 Mordād (1979 July) (Folder 24: 1)
      - Shumārah-i 1-2, 1359 Tir-Day (1980 June-December) (Folder 24: 2)
      - Shumārah-i 2, 6, 7, undated (Folder 24: 3)
    - Nashrī-yi vīzheh-yi bahas durun daw sāzmān, Mujāhidīn-i Khalq va Chirīk'hā-yi Fadā'ī-i, shumārah-i 1, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān-i Chirīk'hā-yi Fadā'ī-i Khalq-i Īrān), journals, 1355 Farvardīn (1976 March) (Folder 24: 4)
    - "Paik-i kār," shumārah'ha-yi 15, 17, 31, 41-42, 44-46, 48-51, newsletters, 1362 Tīr-Esfand (1983 July-1984 March) (Folder 24: 5-6)
    - Payām dānishjoo, dānishjuyān-i pīshru dar khārij az kishvar-havādār rāh-i fadā'i, sāl-i 1, shumārah-i 1-2,4,6-7, journals, 1360 Āzar-1361 Tīr/Mordād (1981 November-1982 June/July) (Folder 24: 7)
    - Payām-i dānishjoo, urgān-i dānishjoo-i sāzmān-i chirīk'hā-yi fadā'i-i khalq, shumārah-i 2-3, booklets, 1357 Mordād (July 1978) (Folder 24: 8)
    - Payām-i Chirīk'hā-yi Fadā'ī-i Khalq, 1357-1361 (1978-1982) (Folder 24: 9-10)
    - Payām-i Fadā'ī-i, sāl-i 1-2, shumārah-i 2 va 10, journals, 1365 Ordibihisht va 1366 Khordād (1986 April and 1987 May) (Folder 24: 11)
    - Payk-i mobārāz, anjumān-i mohasalīn-i īrāni dar berlin gharbī, shumārah-i 1, journals, 1354 Day (1975 December) (Folder 25: 1)
    - Pīshgām dānishāmuz, sāl-i 1, shumārah-i 5, 7-8, 14, newspapers, 1360 Ordibihisht-Tīr (1981 April-June) (Folder 25: 2)
    - Pīshgām, shumārah-i 1, journals, 1358 Farvardīn (1979 March) (Folder 25: 3)
    - Pīshgām 2, sāzmān-i dānishjuyān pīshgām, journals, 1358 Ordibihisht (1979 April) (Folder 25: 4)
    - Qīyām, (New York: s.n.), journals, 1358-1368 (1979-1989) (Folder 25: 5-9)
      - Dawreh-yi 2, shumārah-i 2, 1358 Esfand (1979 February) (Folder 25: 5)
      - Dawreh-yi 2, sāl-i 3, shumārah-'i 1 va 4, 1359 Farvardin va Tīr/Mordād (1979 March and June/July) (Folder 25: 6)
      - Sāl-i 9-10, 12, shumārah-i 1, circa 1365-1368 (1986-1989) (Folder 25: 7-9)
    - Rāh-i Fadā'i-i, shumārah-i 1-2, 4-5, 8-10, booklets, 1358 Shahrivar-1359 Ordibihisht (1979 August-1980 April) (Folder 25: 10-11)
    - Sedāi-yi Fadā'ī-i, rādio-i sāzmān-i chirīk'hā-yi fadā'ī-i khalq-i īrān, shumārah-i 1, pamphlet, 1364 Tīr (1975 June) (Folder 25: 12)
    - Sīyāhkal, sāl-i 1, shumārah-i 1-3, (Houston, Tex.: Intishārat-i 19 Bahman), magazines, 1363 (1984) (Folder 25: 13-15)
    - "Vīzhehnāmeh-yi khabarī," shumārah-i 52, 58, 79-80, 82-83, newsletters, 1365 (1986) (Folder 25: 16)
    - Vīzheh-yi 11 Esfand va 8 Tīr, journals, 1363-1364 (1984-1985) (Folder 25: 17)
    - "Vīzheh-yi 16 Āzar," neshrī-yi dānishjuyān-i pīshgām, newsletter, 1359 Āzar (1980 November) (Folder 25: 18)
    - Vīzheh-yi Noruz, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān), journals, 1362-1364 (1983-1985) (Folder 26: 1)
    - Vīzheh-yi sivvum-i khordād, sāzmān-i sarāsarī dānishjuyān-i īrān dar Amrikā, 1362 (1983) (Folder 26: 2)
    - Zan va mobārzeh, Kumiteh-yi zanān, sāzmān-i dānishjuyān-i dar Amrikā, shumārah-i 1, journal, 1360 Pāiz (1981 Fall) (Folder 26: 3)
    - Newsletters and bulletins, 1356-1364 (1977-1985) (Folder 26: 4-5)
      Includes one newsletter in English observing workers' solidarity
  - Monographs and booklets (Folder 26-34)
    - Against Liquidationism in Defense of Principled Unity, Organization of Iranian Peoples' Fedayan Guerrillas-Majority, (London: International Kar), booklet, 1982 July (Folder 26: 6)
      Includes English translation, abridged, of the "Forward to the First Congress of the Organisation," delivered December 6, 1981
    - "'Aksariyat' S Ch F Kh A zir-i parcham-i susīāl rifurmism," bakhsh 1, fasl-i avval, shumārah-i 11, booklet, 1359 Khordād (1980 May) (Folder 26: 7)